本字幕由 YYeTs人人影視 翻譯創作
歡迎愛好者加入我們  www.YYeTs.com
翻譯： spriteNT   兔子1M   永不永不蒼老 時間軸： 潘叔
校對：小舞 監製：可樂嘻嘻  後期：yyp
我沒射中你的心臟
I just missed your heart.
漢娜
你現在已經死了
You are dead, right now.
我殺了你
I've killed you.
徒手打
Use your hands.
自己把鹿拖回去
Drag the deer back yourself.
怎麼了
What's wrong?
受傷了嗎
Are you hurt?
迷迷糊糊的樣子
You were half asleep.
你得隨時準備好
You must always be ready.
即便是在睡覺
Even when you're sleeping.
反應也要迅速敏捷
Think on your feet.
-非生...  -即死
- Adapt... - Or die.
下次我會做得更好
I'll do better next time.
德語
German.
下次我會做得更好
I'll do better next time.
意大利語
Italian.
下次我會做得更好
I'll do better next time.
西班牙語
Spanish.
Espanol.
真要我扭斷你脖子嗎
Did you really want me to snap your neck?
你把那頭鹿分成多少塊了
How much did you pull off the deer?
120塊
In 120 parts.
共200磅重吧
200 pounds in total.
我想是的
I think so.
這就對了
That explains it.
對什麼
What?
你打我的力度
How you beat me.
你更強壯了
You've getting stronger.
很高興你沒把我的脖子扭斷
I'm glad you didn't snap my neck.
大藍鯨是史上最大的動物
The great blue whale is the largest animal to have ever existed.
它的心臟就重達1300磅
Its heart weighs 1300 pounds.
雄性藍鯨有7加侖大的...
And the male has 7 gallons of...
睪丸
testicles.
500英里外就能聽到藍鯨之樂...
The blue whale's music can be heard for over five hundred miles...
藍鯨舌頭的重量超過2.5噸
A blue whale's tongue weighs over two and a half tons.
音樂什麼樣子
What does music feel like?
音樂  是聲音的組合
Music- a combination of sounds
一種表達美和思想情感的藝術
with a view to beauty of form and expression of emotion.
我想親耳聽聽
I want to hear it for myself.
這堣@應俱全
We've all we need right here.
還不夠
It's not enough.
我準備好了
I'm ready.
爸爸  我準備好了
Papa, I'm ready.
《格林童話》
1  2  3  4  5  6
One, two, three, four, five, six.
我住在德國萊比錫城
I live in Leipzig German city.
人口  70萬
Population: 0.7 million peoples.
再說一次
Tell me again.
威廉·格林小屋  斯提芬街
Wilhelm Grimm's House Stefan Straβe,
21610559  柏林  德國
21610559, Berlin, Germany.
我們住在維琴察廣場7號
We live at number 7, Vicenza Platz.
我就讀於克勞斯學院文理中學
I go to school at The Klaus College Gymnasium.
魯迪·甘特和克萊拉·沙伊茨是我最好的朋友
And my best friends are Rudy Gunter and Clara Scheitz.
威廉·格林小屋  斯提芬街
Wilhelm Grimm's House Stefan Straβe,
21610559  柏林  德國
21610559, Berlin, Germany.
我喜歡文學和運動
I like literature and sport.
特別是網球和田徑
In particular, tennis and athletics.
我們住在維琴察廣場7號
We live at number 7, Vicenza Platz.
我就讀於克勞斯學院文理中學
I go to school at The Klaus College Gymnasium.
魯迪·甘特和克萊拉·沙伊茨是我最好的朋友
And my best friends are Rudy Gunter and Clara Scheitz.
我還有一條小狗叫特魯迪
I also have a dog called Trudy.
我準備好了
I'm ready.
我已經準備好了
I'm ready now.
3  4  5  6
Three, four, five, six.
看到了嗎  聽到了嗎
Did you see it? Did you hear it?
就像打雷一樣  太美了
It's like thunder! It was so beautiful!
那是什麼
What is it?
它能告訴瑪麗莎·維格拉我們的方位
It tells Marissa Wiegler where we are.
如果你覺得準備好了  打算離開這
If you think you're ready, and you want to leave here,
只需打開開關就行
all you have to do is flip that switch.
但一旦觸碰開關  就別無退路
But once it's done there's no going back.
除非你死或者她亡  她決不會放棄
She won't stop until you're dead, or she is.
明白了嗎
You understand?
我不會替你做決定
I won't be there to hold your hand.
自己考慮清楚
So be sure.
想清楚這是不是你的真正所想
Be sure it's what you really want.
它就在這  不急  要想清楚
It's here. There's no rush.
萊卡是莫斯科街頭的一種雜種狗
Laika, a mongrel dog from the street of Moscow,
也是第一隻繞地飛行的動物
was the first animal to orbit the Earth.
1957年11月3日  她被送入外太空
She was launched into outer space on the third of November, 1957.
科學家認為人類
Scientists believe humans
無法忍受外太空的環境
would be unable to survive the conditions of outer space.
因此動物的航天飛行就成了
So flights by animals were used
人類探索外太空的先驅實驗
as experiments precursory to human missions.
那時的火箭是不可回收式的
A rocket was not designed to be retrievable,
萊卡就是去送命的
and Laika has always been, intended to die.
但她沒死  對嗎
But she didn't, did she?
還記得嗎  他們無法收回火箭
They couldn't bring the rocket back, remember?
記得
I remember.
但有時我希望你能換種方式看問題
But sometimes I wish you would read it differently.
當一顆行星瓦解時
When a star collapses,
超新星爆炸所發出的光
the supernova explosion is ten billion times
要比其他行星要亮百億倍
brighter than the other stars.
和我一起去打獵嗎
Will you hunt with me?
如果你想我陪的話
If you want.
隨你吧
Well, it's up to you.
-我嗎  -沒錯
- Me? - Yes.
那我待家
I'll stay.
好  好吧
Yes, good.
瑪麗莎·維格拉
Marissa Wiegler...
來找我吧
come and find me.
你很幸運能獵到那頭鹿
You were lucky to have caught that deer.
今天外面什麼也沒有
There was nothing out there today.
聞著很香
The smell's good.
什麼時候能吃
When will it be ready?
就快了
Soon.
我們接收到一個明碼信號  是自己人
We've picked up an unencrypted signal. One of ours.
-什麼時候  -東部時間6點32分
- When? - 0632 Eastern Standard.
定位北極圈以外60英里附近
Triangulated about 60 miles below the Arctic Circle.
靠近卡祖瑪
Near Kazuma.
我們猜是埃塈J·海勒
We think it is Erik Heller.
-埃塈J·海勒  -他是你負責的吧
- Erik Heller? - You're his handler, right?
對  名字聽上去挺熟
Sure, the name sounds familiar.
美利堅合眾國
該死的埃塈J
Fuck Erik.
為什麼是現在
Why now?
看起來怎麼樣
How does it look?
不錯...
Good...
差不多
Almost good.
埃塈J·海勒  1991年入伍
Erik Heller, recruited in 1991.
他是正式的FSK特工[通信技術工]
Formal FSK operative.
是我們在東歐和中亞反間諜活動中
He became integral to our counter Intelligence Ops
不可或缺的一員
in Eastern europe and Central Asia.
94年後檔案一片空白
His file ends in '94.
1996年4月18日  在約翰娜·祖迪克的屍體邊
There was no sign of life until April 18, 1996,
發現一把帶有他指紋的22口徑魯格手槍
when his fingerprints were found on a 22 calibre ruger,
魯格是美國一家世界名槍公司
此前不知其生死情況
found beside body of one, Johanna Zadek.
約翰娜·祖迪克  1970年出生於德國
Johanna Zadek, born in 1970, German.
1994年  海勒發現並發展了她
She was spotted and developed by Heller in 1994.
-從未受雇  -為什麼發展她
- Never recruited. - Why was she being developed?
文件中沒有記錄  繼續說過去的事
That's not in the file. Let's keep on the past.
海勒很不安分
Heller is a rogue asset.
我建議我們去把他揪出來
I propose we go and pull him out.
我們還有更重要的問題  瑪麗莎
We got bigger problems, Marissa.
讓國際刑警去抓吧
Let Interpol pick him up.
他現在不歸我們管
He's no longer our responsibility.
國際刑警一逮捕他
Interpol nabs him,
BND  FSB和法國方面就會找到他
that exposes him to BND, FSB, France.
BND  德國聯邦情報局
FSB  俄國聯邦安全部門
你們真想每個歐洲情報局
Do you really want every intelligence agency
抓住這個禍害嗎
in Europe scratching at this threat?
-路易斯  -抱歉
- Lewis? - I'm sorry,
這事還是我們自己來解決  先生們
but we need to keep this contained, gentlemen.
別聲張  我與他共過事
Keep it small. I've worked with this man.
他知道些你們不想知道的事
He knows things I don't think you wanna know.
感謝你的坦率
I appreciate your candor.
你有什麼需要  路易斯
What do you need Lewis?
抓一個人  給我一天時間
One man, one-day operation.
-再說一次  -瑪麗莎·維格拉
- Tell me again. - Marissa Wiegler.
-然後  -明信片
- Then? - Postcard.
-再然後  -什麼
- Then? - What?
我們見面的地址
The address where we meet.
威廉·格林小屋  斯提芬街
Wilhelm Grimm House, Stefan Straβe,
21610559  柏林  德國
21610559, Berlin, Germany.
-還有什麼  -非生即死
- Then what else? - Adapt or die.
-反應要迅速敏捷  -即便是在睡覺
- Think on your feet... - Even when I'm sleeping.
爸爸
Papa.
記住我教你的  你會沒事的
Remember what I taught you and you will be fine.
那堥
I'll see you there.
麥考林  聽見嗎
Macalahan, do you read me?
麥考林
Macalahan.
麥考林  聽見嗎
Macalahan, do you read me?
沖  沖  沖
Go, go, go.
埃塈J·海勒逃走了
Erik Heller escaped.
怎麼跑的
How did that happen?
不清楚  我們認為他趁著暴雪跑了或...
Unclear. We think he got away in the snow storm or...
還有比我想像更嚴重的事
And something bigger than that I can manage.
抓一個人  只消一天時間
One man, one day of operations.
找到他  路易斯
Just find him, lewis.
把人給我找出來
Find him and bring him to me.
還有個孩子  事情出人意料
There was a kid. Things got out of our control!
維格拉
Wiegler?
維格拉  你在聽嗎
Wiegler, are you there?
她現在哪
Where is she now?
你好  漢娜
Hello, Hanna.
你好
Hello.
我是伯頓醫生  樂意和我談談嗎
My name is Dr. Burton. Would you like to talk to me?
爸爸告訴我凡事得先佔上風
I was told by my father to gain the upper hand.
很有意思
That's very interesting.
你爸爸還告訴了你什麼
What else did your father tell you?
我在哪
Where am I?
有人守著你
You are in holding.
我從沒見過這樣的房間
I've never been in a room like this.
這對你來說肯定很怪
Must all be very strange for you.
你在森林埵矰F多久
How long have you been in the forest?
漢娜
Hanna?
-那些是攝像頭嗎  -對
- Are those cameras? - Uhuh.
現在它們就在拍攝我們
They're taking our pictures right now,
在做記錄
to keep a record.
你有什麼感受
How does that make you feel?
隱藏的攝像頭...
Camera obscure...
拉丁語中暗室的意思
It's Latin, for dark chamber.
1021年  阿拉伯科學家
It was first described by the Arabic scientist
伊本·海塞姆首次命名了它
Ibn al-Haytham in the year 1021.
把信號傳送至蘭利
Plug the cctv through to Langley.
蘭利  美國中央情報局本部
嘿  你得給她做個全面的精神分析
Hey, you should have a visual on the psych evaluation there.
要我拿點什麼給你嗎  你喜歡什麼
Can I get you something? What do you like?
音樂還是雜誌
Music, magazines.
儘管開口  什麼都行
Just ask, anything.
我想和瑪麗莎·維格拉談談
I want to speak to Marissa Wiegler.
-告訴她我今晚就去  -我能處理
- Tell her I'll be there tonight. - I can handle this.
按我說的做
Just do what you're told.
約翰  快看看這孩子的血樣
John, take a look at this kid's blood sample.
-沒弄錯吧  -是嗎
- Is that right? - Is it?
-不可能吧  -這是她頭髮的樣本
- Can't be right. - Got a sample of her hair.
肯定污染了  再做一次
Must be contaminated. Run it again.
我是瑪麗莎·維格拉
My name is Marissa Wiegler.
你想和我談談嗎
You wanted to speak with me?
去外面等著我
You can wait outside.
我在哪
Where am I?
一個安全的地方  寶貝
You are in a safe place, sweetie.
你是在哪媢J見我的爸爸
Where did you meet my father?
埃塈J
Erik.
你指埃塈J嗎
You mean Erik?
是的
Yes.
我是在東柏林亞歷山大廣場的一個報亭遇見他
I met him by a news kiosk at Alexander Platz. East Berlin.
我在一個報亭遇見了他
I met him at a news kiosk,
-在亞歷山大廣場...  -下著雨
- Alexander Platz... - Say it was raining.
當時還下著雨
in the rain.
他剛從布格拉回來
He'd just arrived from Prague.
你知道你爸爸在哪媔
You know where your father is?
他告訴你他去哪堣F嗎
Did he tell you where he was going?
我們都很擔心他
We are worried about him.
沒事的
It's okay.
特工  注意保持距離
Agent, keep your distance.
沒事的
It's okay.
你要我給她點什麼嗎
Do you want me to give her something?
我覺得很有必要
I think that might be necessary.
快停止
Abort.
打開
Open up.
我再說一遍  特工  快停止
I repeat, agent, abort!
維格拉
Wiegler!
所有人立刻集合
I want everyone here now.
別讓她逃出走廊
Do not let it escape from the gallery.
檢驗報告
-你說她逃出去了嗎  -不可能
- Do you think she got out? - She can't get out.
通知所有部門
Detail every unit available.
已結案
德國護照
媽媽
Mama.
她永遠不會是你的
She will never be yours.
嘿  你好
Hey, hello.
你會說英語嗎
Don't you speak English?
不會也不是你的錯
It's not your fault if you can't.
艾瑪·艾克堛膘鴗K歲才會說英語
Emma Ackery couldn't speak English until she was eight,
因為那時她就像個來自斯里蘭卡的難民
because she was like, a refugee or something from Sri Lanka.
但現在她是個歌星  在美國也很有名
But now she's a pop star, in America too.
所以別擔心現在不會說英語
So don't worry if you can't speak English yet.
她是誰
Who's she?
我找到了她  她不會說英語
I found her, she can't speak English.
她來自斯里蘭卡
She's from Sri Lanka.
我來自德國
I'm from Germany.
我住在萊比錫城  人口70萬
I live in Leipzig. Population: 0.7 million peoples.
我們住在維琴察廣場7號
We live at No. 7 Vicenza Platz.
我喜歡文學和運動
I like literature and sport,
特別是網球和田徑
in particular tennis and athletics.
我就讀於克勞斯學院文理中學
I go to school at The Klaus College Gymnasium.
魯迪·甘特和克萊拉·沙伊茨是我最好的朋友
And my best friends are Rudy Gunter and Clara Scheitz.
聽起來蠻有趣
They sound fun.
我還有一條小狗叫特魯迪
I also have a dog called Trudy.
我們以前有條叫文森特的小狗
We had a dog called Vincent,
但它發瘋死了
but he went mad and died.
索菲  快來
Sophie, come on.
再見
See ya.
索菲  快來
Sophie, come on.
我叫索菲  那是我弟弟邁爾斯
I'm Sophie and that is my brother, Miles.
我叫漢娜
I am...Hanna.
要搭便車嗎
Do you need a lift somewhere?
不了  我更喜歡走路
No. I prefer to walk.
隨你的便
Suit yourself.
索菲  快點  就等你了
Sophie, come on, we are all waiting for you.
監視器顯示她在沙漠
Tacticle says she's in the desert,
在我們的東南方
south east of vessel we're in.
全力追捕海勒
Focus all operations on Heller.
你的意思是這女孩對我們沒價值嗎
Are you saying the girl's not of interest to us?
她當然有用  路易斯
Yes, of course she's of interest, Lewis.
但她還不會
But not an immediate threat
對美國的安全構成直接威脅
to the security of the United States of America.
埃塈J·海勒是眼下最危險的人物  以他為重
Erik Heller is the immediate threat. Focus on Heller.
魯拜賓館
你的家人呢
Where is your family?
-你是阿拉伯人嗎  -我是摩洛哥人
- Are you Arabic? - I am Moroccan.
摩洛哥  首都是拉巴特
Morocco. Capital city: Rabat.
著名景點包括馬拉喀什和索維拉
Places of interest: Marrakech, Essaouira.
信奉伊斯蘭教  語種為阿拉伯語
Religion: Islam. Language: Arabic.
我很喜歡阿拉伯語
I like Arabic very much.
像日語一樣  是個豐富的語言
It's like Japanese, it's big.
你會說阿拉伯語嗎
You speak Arabic?
當然會說
Yes, of course.
你的家人在哪兒
Where is your family?
我今晚要找個地方住
I need a room for the night.
但我沒錢  你能幫幫我嗎
Can you help? I have no money.
這是我們這兒最好的房間
It's the best we've got.
謝謝
Thank you.
每個房間都有這東西嗎
Do you have one of these in every room?
所有的房間都有
All the rooms are the same.
是電
It's electricity.
還用說嗎  都是現代化設備
Of course, all mod cons.
我對電知之甚少
I know a little about electricity.
人們說是愛迪生發明了電
They say Edison invented it.
還是富蘭克林來著
Or was it Franklin?
反正是個美國人
Some American I'm sure.
這個是電熱水壺
This is an electrical kettle.
專為英國人準備的
It's for the English.
他們喜歡自己燒水沏茶
They like to make their own tea.
這是什麼
What is it?
有這就夠不錯的了
It's the best we can do.
你從哪兒來
Where do you come from?
森林
The forest.
是那個德國女孩
It's the German girl.
穿摩洛哥寬長袍的德國佬
It's Kraut in a big Djellaba.
即像雛妓又像拉拉
Like quail or lesbo.
我覺得當個拉拉也挺不錯的
I think I'd quite like to be lesbian.
但我的戀人不能太胖  得像模特一樣
But not one of those fat ones, one who's like, a supermodel.
但也只是玩玩兒  我應該還是會嫁個男人
But who don't hold hands, and I think I'd probably marry a man.
什麼
What?
不親一個嗎
No kiss?
她對你來說有點太老了吧
She's a bit old for you, isn't she?
她是個人妖
She has male and female genetalias.
這就是你為之傾倒的原因吧
And you love her just the way she is.
我很樂意滿足他人的需求
I like to give people what they want.
薇拉  給我朋友來杯美酒
Vera, make my friend something sweet.
還是下次吧
I'll save it for when I need it.
你為何而來  瑪麗莎
What do you want, Marissa?
埃塈J·海勒還活著
Erik Heller's still alive.
意料之中
Of course.
還有那個女孩
And the girl.
你到底為什麼來這
Why are you here precisely?
我需要你
I need you.
需要我這個不中用的老傢伙  真是受寵若驚
You need me? Little old me! I'm very flattered.
我需要你的聰明才智  親愛的
I need your talents, darling.
我需要你幫我做點
I need you to do things
情報局不允許的事情
my agency will not let me do.
停
Stop!
重來
Again.
從頭來
Start again.
細節決定成敗  不是嗎
The devil is in the details, isn't it?
解決那個女孩還是埃塈J
It's the girl or Erik?
她就在摩洛哥
She is in Morocco.
你需要的都在信封
It's all in the envelope.
埃塈J就交給我吧
Let me worry about Erik.
要殺死她嗎
Shall I kill her?
找到她就好
Just find her.
瑪麗莎
Marissa.
她跟你預想的一樣嗎
Did she turn out as you hoped?
比我想的還要好
Better.
重來一遍
Once more.
再來一次
Again.
還告訴我許多
...and gave me lots of advices
關於如何花錢避稅的建議
about how to spend these money do these taxes.
雖然她很漂亮
You see even though she is beautiful,
但還是很會精打細算
she is actually brilliant with money.
別碰我
Get off.
比如有次紀念日  他說有1萬5千塊
Like for one of the anniversary, he said his 15 grand,
是買個愛馬仕凱莉包還是做個隆胸手術呢
for a Hermes kelly bag or a boob job.
而她卻知道
Now she said she knew that the
乳房假體每十年就要更換一次
boob implant will have to be replaced every 10 years.
而愛馬仕凱莉包可是永不貶值
But that the Hermes kelly bag never depreciates in value.
隆胸就說到這兒吧
That's enough for the boob job.
可不是誰都懂這些的
I mean that's not just common sense.
所以我才喜歡她
And that's why I really love her.
我媽反對整形
Mum is against plastic surgery.
-沒錯  -甚至連化妝都很少
- I am. - Mum doesn't even wear make-up.
對  我覺得那很虛偽
I don't. I think it's dishonest.
這就是我的樣子  不喜歡拉倒
This is my face, take it or leave it.
如果你學過美術史和人類學的話
If you study History of Art, Anthropology...
瑞秋是劍橋的優等生
Rachel got a first at Cambridge.
你就會學到紅唇能刺激性慾
you'll learn that red lipstick mimics arousal
且能使人聯想起小陰唇的形狀
and suggests the geography of the labia minora.
-噁心  -而我的嘴唇紅得很自然
- Puke! - Where as I have a lot of natural red pigments
所以我根本不需要塗口紅
in my lips and so I really don't need it.
-太噁心了  -索菲
- Vomitory - Sophie!
-真難為情  -別老跟個孩子似的好嗎
- It's embarrassing. - Just grow up! All right?
-別跟個孩子似的  -對
- Grow up? - Yeah
可是昨天媽媽還讓我
Oh, because yesterday mum was saying
別像個小大人似的
how I shouldn't act beyond my years.
她確實被弄糊塗了  親愛的
No, it does leave her with mixed messages, darling.
因為咱們都想告訴她
Because we're trying to
如何過個快樂的童年
communicate to her how to enjoy childhood.
我只想讓她別再說噁心
I just want her to stop saying vomitory, all right?
這可不好笑
Oi, It's not funny.
漢娜  漢娜
So, Hanna. Hanna?
我很佩服你這麼小就獨自旅行
I'm quite impressed about you traveling around on your own.
我父親鼓勵我學會自立
My father encourages me to be independent.
真不錯
You see, that's wonderful.
我在你這年紀的時候也是個背包客
I was back packing at your age.
那你父親人呢
And where is he, your father?
我花了整整一個美妙的夏天環遊希臘
I spent a heavenly summer, just island hopping around Greece.
環遊希臘
Island hopping around Greece!
怎麼了  挺好的  真的
What? No. It's valuable.
不同的閱歷造就了不同的人
Our experience makes us who we are.
對嗎  孩子們
Isn't that right, kids?
漢娜  你父母還在一起嗎
So Hanna, is your mum and dad still together?
我母親去世了
My mother is dead.
瞧你問的  老爸
Nice one, dad!
真替你難過  我母親也在我小時候就去世了
I'm sorry to hear that. I lost my mum when I was very young, so...
沒關係  很久以前的事了
It's all right. It happened a long time ago.
漢娜
Hanna,
你媽媽怎麼去世的
what did your mum die of?
三發子彈
Three bullets.
天吶  太可怕了
Oh my god, That's appalling!
聲音的組合
Combination of sounds
一種表達美
with a view to beauty of form
和思想感情的藝術
and expression of emotion..
檢驗報告
異常
"Abnormal."
萬一下雨了呢
What happen if it rains?
那你就要淋濕了唄
Well, you going to get wet. Aren't you?
因為天窗被人打破了
Because someone broke the sunroof.
-你媽和我  -是你父母
- The thing is me and your mother are... - Your mother and I...
你媽和我  你父母
The thing is me and your mother, your mother and I
都是成年人  不像你們倆
are responsible adults... not as you two.
我的指甲又感染了
My fungus nail infection's back.
你是誰
Who are you?
你們找那個女孩幹什麼
What do you want from the girl?
我是她的舅舅
I am her uncle.
我們都很擔心她
We are very concerned about her.
我不知道你到底要找什麼
I don't know what you're looking for.
她來過  很友善  然後就離開了
She came, she was nice, she left.
說對了
Bingo!
可不是嘛
Voila!
車上的人已經結賬走了嗎
The van has checked out?
今天剛走
Today.
往北還是往南去了
North or south?
去渡口了  他們要坐渡輪去西班牙
The ferry. They caugh the ferry to Spain.
借你的筆用一下行嗎
Can you lend me your pen?
我已經聯繫了國際刑警
I've contacted Interpol.
誰給你的權利
On whose authority?
沃特  我們不能再隱瞞下去了
Walt. We can't keep this to ourselves anymore.
-你沒聽我說嗎  -他殺了兩個警察
- Were you not listening? - He killed two policemen.
情況變複雜了  我們已無法控制
He's reframed the situation. It is out of our control.
那就讓一切重回掌控之中  路易斯先生
Then we must regain control, Mr. Lewis.
除了我沒人能再見到埃塈J·海勒
I am the first and the last person Erik Heller will see.
懂了嗎
Are we clear?
你聽懂了嗎
-路易斯先生  -遵命
- Mr. Lewis? - Yes, madam.
巫婆死了
天吶  你怎麼在這
Oh, my god! What are you doing here?
天窗是你打破的吧
The sunroof, was it you?
我是不是不該這麼做
Would it be very bad if it was?
也就是說你一直都在我們的車上
You mean you were in the van, the whole time?
要是我爸知道了一定會犯心臟病的
My dad would have a heart attack if he found out.
-你會告訴他嗎  -漢娜  你瘋了嗎
- Will you have to tell him? - Hanna, you are so mental!
我當然不會告訴他
Of course I'm not going to tell him.
我覺得你很厲害
I think it's brilliant.
-那你有地方待嗎  -沒有
- Have you got anywhere to stay? - No.
現在有了  你可以跟我待在一起
Yes, you do. You're staying with me.
可以嗎
I am?
當然可以
Yeah, obviously.
我可以把你藏起來  但你得答應我一個條件
I'm sneaking you in, on one condition.
什麼條件
What?
那些西班牙男孩  帥極了
These boys. Spanish. Gorgeous.
不  別回頭  他們像球員一樣皮膚健康
No, don't look. Don't go all pruny about it, like footballers.
也沒有修眉什麼的
Haven't got their eyebrows waxed, or anything!
-好  -總之我們今晚要出去玩  你也來
- Good. - Anyway, we're going out tonight and you have to come.
-好吧  -天吶  你真好說話  瘋丫頭
- All right. -God, you're not hard to convince! Perv.
什麼
Who?
你有什麼衣服穿嗎
Have you got anything to wear?
你可不能穿這個  看起來像個德國瘋子
You can't wear those, you look like some mad German.
害怕嗎
Are you scared?
有什麼可怕的
Of what?
我們現在要接吻嗎
Are we going to kiss now?
你願意嗎
Would you like to?
接吻會帶動34塊面部肌肉
Kissing requires a total of 34 facial muscles
以及112塊肢體肌肉
and 112 postural muscles.
而其中起主導作用的是
The most important muscle involved
口輪匝肌
is the orbicularis oris muscle,
因為要靠它來噘起嘴唇
because it is used to pucker the lips.
漢娜  你這個瘋子
Hanna, you mentalist!
跟你朋友說  我就是想吻她一下
Please tell your friend I wanted just a kiss.
漢娜
Hanna!
-我該放開他嗎  -不然你以為呢
- Should I let him go? - As opposed to what?
當然  快放開他
Yes, you should let him go!
我要走了
I'm going to go now.
好
Okay.
今晚很美好
It was nice.
是你嗎  索菲
Sophie, is that you?
是睡魔來了
It is the sandman.
繼續睡吧
Go to sleep.
天吶  你跟個土匪似的  真丟人
Oh, my god. You acted like a bandit. It's embarrassing.
-我怎麼了  -我真服你了
- Like what? - Oh, I can't believe you.
喂  媽媽
Hello, mama.
我知道你對我很失望
I know you're disappointed in me.
我懂  抱歉  媽媽
I know it. I am very sorry, Mama.
但是  我也許找到了一個好辦法
But... But maybe I've found a way to make it better.
我參與了一個項目
I'm in a programme now.
一個讓嬰兒更強壯的項目
A programme to make babies stronger.
是個美國的項目  很科...
It's an American programme, very scien...
你是怎麼進來的  維格拉女士
How did you get into my house, Mrs. Wiegler?
我是來找埃塈J的
I'm looking for Erik.
他說你已經死了
He said you were dead.
也就是說你見過他
So you've seen him?
他只捎過口信
He sent word.
漢娜在哪兒
Where is Hanna?
你沒有過孩子吧
Did you ever have children of your own?
我有其他重要的事做
I made certain choices.
那你永遠也無法體會
Then you will never understand
失去孩子的痛苦
what it is like to lose your child,
以及發生的一切
to not know what happened.
年復一年的漫長等待
The years of waiting,
無數次向窗外望去
of watching from the window.
靜靜地等待
And waiting...
等待
Waiting...
你見到她了嗎
Have you seen her?
漢娜
Hanna!
她長什麼樣子呢
Can you tell me what she looks like?
跟她媽媽很像
Like her mother.
-漢娜  -什麼事
- Hanna? - Yes.
你到底從哪兒來
Where do you really come from?
萊比錫城  我住在那
Leipzig. I live in Leipzig.
如果我們是朋友的話
If we're going to be friends,
就應該坦誠相待
you're going to have to be honest with me.
這是規矩
Those are the rules.
-我們是朋友了嗎  -是啊
- Are we friends? - Yes.
我挺喜歡你的
I like you.
有朋友真好
I'd like to have a friend.
雖然你瘋瘋癲癲的  但是我喜歡你
I mean, you're a freak and everything, but I like you.
我也喜歡你  真的
I like you too. I really do.
但是
But.
有些事情不能告訴你
There are things I can't tell you.
-你明白嗎  -明白
- Do you understand? - Yes
其實不太明白
Actually, no, I don't.
有些人想要傷害我
There are peoples that want to harm me.
-一些壞人  -瞭解
- Bad peoples. - I see.
-他們會窮追不捨  -是啊
- And they won't stop. - Right.
所以為了你的安全著想
So, for your own safety.
那我們還是朋友嗎
Can we still be friends?
不知道
I don't know.
我都不知道你到底是誰
I mean I don't really know who you are, do I?
本該如此
That's just it.
我都不瞭解自己
Neither do I.
-這是什麼  -關於我的報告
- What is it? - It's something about me.
我知道DNA的意思  但別的就不懂了
I know what DNA means, but I don't understand the rest of it.
-你病了嗎  -我覺得不是
- Are you sick? - I don't feel sick.
-你有什麼毛病呢  -我沒毛病
- What's wrong with you? - Nothing's wrong with me.
你接下來要幹什麼呢
What are you going to do?
我要去柏林
I'm going to Berlin.
我要去威廉·格林小屋和我父親會合
I have to meet meet my father at the House of Wilhelm Grimm.
寫格林童話的那個嗎
From Grimms fairy tales?
沒錯
That's right.
既然你這麼說
If you say so.
我又說錯話了嗎
Did I say the wrong thing again?
這個給你
Keep this.
別忘了我
To remember me.
這是代表友誼的手鐲
It's a friendship bracelet.
謝謝你
Thank you.
漢娜在哪
Where's Hanna?
你看上去糟透了  要不要喝點茶
Wow, you look rough! Do want some tea?
我喝過了  誰是漢娜
I had some. Who's Hanna?
在摩洛哥跟我們一起吃飯的女孩
The girl we ate dinner with in Morocco.
她在這  或說曾在  昨晚她和我一起出去
She's here, or was. She came out with me last night.
她怎麼來的  跟她父親一起嗎
How did she get here? Is she with her father?
不是  她自己來的
No, she came on her own.
什麼
What?
人們有自己教育孩子的方式
Look, other people have their own style of parenting.
他提倡獨立性
He's promoting independence.
她像個孤兒一樣  是我太保守了吧
She's like an orphan! Call me conservative.
-你真的很保守嗎  親愛的  -我才不是
- Are you really conservative, darling? - No, I'm not.
我說我們可以順路帶她去里昂
I said we'll give her a lift to Lyon.
我們下一站是去里昂吧
We are going to Lyon, aren't we?
我找到了早餐
I found breakfast.
好噁心啊
That's gross!
我們發現他了  我們發現海勒了
We've got him! We have Heller.
聽到了嗎  帶他去見維格拉
Do you read me? Bring him to Wiegler.
她會安排審問
She will id an interview.
她是那樣說的嗎
Is that what she said?
兩分鐘前剛確認過
Confirmed with her two minutes ago.
瑪麗莎  靠
Marissa, damn it!
在鄉下我覺得很踏實
I feel so grounded in the countryside.
城市讓我窒息
The city stifles me,
壓抑著我的情緒  創造力和精神
emotionally, creatively, spiritually.
這樣的地方讓我們更接近上帝
Places like this bring us closer to God.
上帝
God?
不是很現代的感覺
Well, not any modernistic sense.
佛祖  克利須那  我們的上帝
Buddha, Krishna, the God within.
克利須那是印度教的神祇
無論你信仰什麼
Whatever you believe in.
你有信仰嗎  漢娜
What do you believe in, Hanna?
沒有
Nothing.
你沒事吧
Everything alright?
我想是的
I think so.
我不知道孩子是不是能聽到我說話
I'm not sure if it's true that the baby can hear me,
但在夜晚我能感受到她
but at night I feel her.
我希望她能聽到我說話
I hope she hears me.
你也曾有這樣的感覺嗎  媽媽
Was it like this for you, mama?
我想我知道她的樣子
I think I know what she looks like.
當我閉上眼睛就能看到她
I can see her when I close my eyes.
我能聽到她在我身體  胎動
I can hear her inside me. Movings.
我是不是很傻  我想應該是個女孩
Do you think is that silly? Oh, I think it's a girl.
希望是
I hope so.
埃塈J
Erik ...
怎麼了
What?
老天  路易斯
Oh for Christ's sake, Lewis.
你好  瑪麗莎
Hello, Marissa.
我聽說你死了
I heard you were dead.
是你女兒告訴你的嗎
Did your little girl tell you that?
-你在聽什麼  -自救
- What are you listening to? - Self help.
你需要幫助嗎
Are you in need of help?
很高興聽你說話
It's good to hear you.
路易斯  派技術組
沒想到我們還有機會說話
I didn't imagine we'd have the chance to talk.
你還沒抓到她吧  你沒那本事
You don't have her, do you? You're not that good.
埃塈J  你真會調情
Oh, Erik! You're such a flirt.
技術組馬上到
Tech's on the way.
你曾是個出色的特工  埃塈J
You were a good agent, Erik.
看你現在這德行真讓人心疼
Sad to see you go dumb.
我錯過了什麼
What did I miss?
我不能再這樣做了
I couldn't do it anymore.
那些我們做過的事
The things we did.
約翰娜的事我很抱歉
I... I'm sorry with Johanna.
不止漢娜  還有所有那些人
With all of them. With Hanna.
為什麼現在回來
So, why come back now?
技術組的人
Tech guys.
我問你呢  埃塈J
I asked you a question, Erik?
埃塈J  你還在嗎
Erik, are you still there?
行動  出發
Move. Get up.
靠  靠  靠
Shit ... shit ... shit ...
漢娜  我想我們迷路了
Hanna, I think we're lost.
-我得靠邊停下  -別這樣做
- I have to pull over. - No, don't.
看不清地圖
Can't see the map.
停下來了吧  我想撒尿
Have we stopped? I need to pee.
別走太遠哦  寶貝
Don't want you going too far right now, love.
我覺得你還是別動的好  索菲
I think you should stay where you are, Sophie.
怎麼了  漢娜
Hanna, what's going on?
穩住
Keep calm.
-我們到里昂了嗎  -還沒
- Are we are in Lyon? - No, we're not.
你想怎樣都行  就是別跟著我
Whatever you do, don't follow me!
答應我別跟著我
Promise not to follow me.
我答應你
I promise.
謝謝你做我的朋友
Thank you for being my friend.
漢娜
Hanna!
行動
Come on, come on!
閉嘴  別說話
Silence! Shut up!
漢娜
Hanna.
太奇怪了  完全沒道理
Definitely odd. Disconnected.
我覺得我和孩子關係不錯
You know, I like to think that I have a rapport with kids.
我跟他們處得不錯
You know, I get with them.
先生  這種時候
You know, sir, it's days like this
我尤其痛恨我的工作
that I really hate my job.
是啊  我懂
Yeah, I'm sure you do.
真的真的很難受
This is very, very difficult.
但有時候孩子們也不是好東西
But sometimes children are bad people too.
-別哭了  -我什麼都不會告訴你
- Stop crying. - I'm not telling you anything!
-你認識這個男孩嗎  -不認識
- Do you know this boy? - No!
他認識你  你的朋友很危險
He knows you. Your friend is in a lot of danger.
我什麼都不知道
I don't know anything!
她說自己住在萊比錫城
She said she lived in Leipzig.
就讀於克勞斯學院文理中學
She went to The Klaus College Gymnazium.
她的朋友叫魯迪和甘特
Her friends were Rudy and Gunter
她喜歡網球  有一隻叫做特魯迪的狗
She likes tennis and she has a dog named Trudy.
-她撒謊了  -顯然
- She lied to you. - Absolutely.
她沒有完全迷失
She is not lost.
但她需要照顧
But she needed taken care of.
我有東西給你看
I've got something to show you.
-母親的照顧  -這就是漢娜的母親
- A little help from mom. - This is Hanna's mother.
親生母親
Biological mother.
15年前  在一次野營中
15 years ago, she was shot to death
漢娜的爸爸槍殺了她
by Hanna's father on a camping trip.
想看看堶悸漯F西嗎
Don't you wanna see what's inside?
-說求你  -求你了
- Say "Please." - Please.
你是不是喜歡她
You like her, don't you?
沒關係  我不會告訴任何人
It's okay. I won't tell anyone.
她很漂亮
She's very pretty.
-她在哪  -這要你告訴我
- Where is she? - You tell me.
她有麻煩了嗎
Is she in lots of trouble?
非常大的麻煩  親愛的
The worst kind, sweetheart.
有些壞人在找她
Some very bad men are looking for her,
我要找到她  我想要保護她
and I need to find her. I wanna protect her.
你想讓她受到傷害嗎
Do you want her to get hurt?
不想
No.
她要去柏林  去威廉·格林小屋
She's going to Berlin. To Wilhelm Grimm's house.
去見她的爸爸
To meet her dad.
漢娜  是你  快進來
Hanna. Hanna ... Hanna come, come.
這邊
This way.
等你了好久
Been waiting for you a long time.
埃塈J是怎麼跟你說我的
What did Erik told you about me?
威廉·格林小屋  斯提芬街
Wilhelm Grimm's House Stefan Straβe,
21610559  柏林  德國
21610559, Berlin, Germany.
沒錯
That's it.
他沒說過我的魔術吧
He didn't tell you of my magic.
克勞斯  09/05  週二見  埃塈J
Klaus, 09/05. Be there Tuesday. Erik.
-是哪天  -就是今天啊  親愛的
- What day is it? - It's today, my dear.
過來
Come, come.
坐這
Sit.
你餓了吧
Oh, you're hungry.
-華夫餅  -我能吃一個嗎
- Waffles. - May I have one?
雞蛋嗎  當然可以
An egg? Of course.
你想吃什麼都行  親愛的
You can eat whatever you want, my dear.
我的鞋也行
My shoe!
我差點忘了
Oh, I've almost forgotten.
一個禮物
A present.
給我的
For me?
你需要張近照
You will need a fresh photograph.
不過都安排好了是嗎
But everything's in order, yes?
為什麼我要這張紙來告訴我自己的名字
Why do I need a piece of paper to tell me my name?
不是給你用的  親愛的
Not you, not you, my dear.
但是我們其他人需要紙和電腦
But everyone else we need paper and computers,
這樣我們就不用
so we don't have to ask people their names
當面問人們的名字了
to look them in the face.
你長得很好看
You have a good face.
你跟你爸爸長得一模一樣
You look just like your father.
就連走路的姿勢都像
And you walk like him too, uh uh uh.
我才不那樣走路
I don't walk like that.
你就是這樣走路的  親愛的
Yes, you do! You do, my dear! Uh uh.
你也認識我媽媽嗎
Did you know my mother too?
當然
Of course.
她是個歌手  出色的歌手
She was a singer. A wonderful singer.
你愛唱歌嗎
Do you sing?
爸爸  埃塈J沒教我
Papa.. Erik, didn't teach me.
可憐的孩子
Oh, you poor child.
他還真是把世上的好東西
He has truely limited you from all the wonderful things
都跟你分開了
the world has to offer.
沒有魔術
No magic.
沒有音樂
No music.
我會教你的
I'll teach you.
是他來了嗎
Is that him?
快到樓上去  親愛的  快去
Upstairs with you, my dear. Quickly.
你好啊
Good day.
我們關門了  孩子們
We're closed, boys and girls.
埃塈J在哪
Where is Erik?
他知道的不多
He doesn't know much
或者他很會撒謊
or he is a very good liar.
他認識約翰娜
He knew Johanna.
顯然
Yes, of course.
還知道一點點項目的事
Bits and pieces about the programme.
對於女孩的事他都知道什麼
What does he know about the girl?
他認為埃塈J是她的父親
He thinks Erik's the father.
-所有人都認為埃塈J是她父親  -真有趣
- Everybody thinks Erik's the father. - That's precious!
你好  我是瑪麗莎·維格拉
Yes? This is Marissa Wiegler.
沃特  我沒認出...
Walt, I didn't recog....
路易斯死了
Lewis is dead.
你不覺得這事應該告訴我們嗎
Do you think it's important to tell us?
為什麼還不告訴我們
Why didn't you call us yet?
抓一個人  只消一天時間
One man, one-day operation.
是啊  我們都想念路易斯
Yes. Yes. Yes! We all want Lewis.
他是被穿門而入的子彈打死的  沃特
He was shooting through the door, Walt.
不  我不會停下
No, I'm not standing down...
不  我有興趣...
No, I'm interest..
好吧  是時候了
Well, yes. That is time.
聽著  沃特
No, listen, Walt.
干擾
母體子宮DNA干擾
未經科學界准許
人體試驗
偽科學
海辛格
Heizinger.
出發去外婆家  走
So off to grandmother's house, we go.
你見過她嗎
Have you seen her?
漢娜
Hanna!
坐下
Sit down.
你是我的爸爸嗎
Are you my father?
坐下  漢娜
Sit down, Hanna.
-你是我爸爸嗎  -坐下吧
- Are you my father? - Please, sit.
是不是
Are you?
我當然是你父親了  漢娜
Hanna, of course I'm your father.
-我養大了你  -可瑪麗莎說
- I raised you. - But Marissa said ...
-漢娜  -別騙我
- Hanna! - Don't lie to me!
我是你的父親  我一直陪著你長大
I'm your father. I've been with you your whole life.
把你當做親生骨肉
Treated you like my own flesh and blood.
但我不是你的親生骨肉
But I was not your flesh and blood.
-我是不是不正常  -不是
- I am abnormal? - No!
我在哪出生
Where was I born?
告訴我真相
Tell me the truth.
你在一所研究機構誕生
You were born in a research facility.
在波蘭的農村  戈林加
In rural Poland, Galinki.
是什麼樣的研究
What was the research?
他們取出受精卵
They took fertilized embryos
對它們做一些小小的改進
and made small changes to them to improve them.
減少人的恐懼和同情心
To reduce the capacity for fear, for pity,
增強肌肉力量
to increase muscle strength,
強化感官  一切為了造就更強的戰士
heightened senses. Anything to make a better soldier.
完美的戰士
The perfect soldier.
我在一家墮胎診所徵募了你的媽媽
I've recruited your mother in an abortion clinic.
同樣的  我還找了另外20個孕婦
I've recruited twenty women the same way.
-你是說還有其他孩子嗎  -是的
- There were other children? - Yes.
在你兩歲時
When you were two,
瑪麗莎·維格拉終止了整個項目
Marissa Wiegler, she closed the whole programme
所有的研究
and all of this research,
全部廢棄
it was disposed of.
懂了嗎
Do you understand?
我愛你  漢娜  這點你要明白
I love you, Hanna. You have to know that.
因為我是個怪胎嗎
Because I'm a freak?
不
No.
因為你是我的孩子
Because you are my child.
你要去哪
Where are you going?
別這樣
Stop this.
讓我走
Let me go!
別這樣
Stop this.
漢娜  漢娜  求你了
Hanna! Hanna, please!
我一直在為你以後的生活做準備
I tried to prepare you for what your life'd be.
但你沒教我該如何面對這事
You didn't prepare me for this.
快跑
Run!
搞定他
Take it.
你就這點本事嗎
That's all you got?
跑啊  豬頭
Run, pig!
為什麼是現在  埃塈J
Why now, Erik?
孩子長大了
Kids grow up.
格林先生
Mr. Grimm!
Mr. Grimm.
漢娜
Hanna
我在這  漢娜
I'm here, Hanna.
別擔心  親愛的
Oh, don't worry sweetheart.
站住  別再靠近我
Don't! Don't move any closer!
漢娜  我能幫你
Hanna, I can help you.
求你了
Please!
我不想再傷害任何人
I don't want to hurt anyone anymore..
我只是想聊聊
I just wanna talk.
結束了  瑪麗莎
It's over now, Marissa.
讓我走吧
Let me go.
漢娜
Hanna!
別想逃走  丫頭
Don't walk away from me, young lady!
我沒射中你的心臟
I just missed your heart
漢娜